<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Scion</name>
		<description>Scion Background</description>
		<author url="">Eldritch Hunt</author>
		<update version="1.0.0">
			<file name="background-scion.xml" url=""/>
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Scion" type="Background" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_BACKGROUND_SCION">
		<description>
			<p>You are a member of the Scions, a group of brilliant, boundary-pushing scientists, working at the fringe of societal norms and scientific understanding. You have seen life being breathed into the lifeless, creating living constructs through electrifying science, a practice never seen before. As a member of the Scions, the inventions and creations of your group have earned favor among the city's higher-ups, and given delusions of grandeur to those of you who wrestle with the godlike power of creation at your fingertips. </p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong>Arcana, Investigation</li>
                <li><strong>Languages:</strong>: :One of your choiuce </li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies</strong>Tinker's tools, one type of artisan's tools of your choice</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong>A set of tinker's tools, a set of artisan's tools, a notebook full of your scientific sketches and notes, a bottle of black ink, a quill, a small experimental creation of your design, and a pouch containing 15 gp </li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SCION_CREATION" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
			<p>As a Scion, you have been at the forefront of scientific exploration and innovation. The thrill of discovery and the power to create or reanimate life fill you with excitement or perhaps existential dread. The impact of your inventions on society and the moral implications of your work are things you grapple with. </p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Arcana, Investigation, 1 Language, Tinker Tools, Artisan Tool</set>
        </setters>
		<rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_ARCANA"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_INVESTIGATION"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_TINKERS_TOOLS"/>
            <select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Scion)" supports="Artisan tools"/>
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Scion)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SCION_CREATION"/>
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I am relentlessly curious and always eager to learn something new.</item>
                <item id="2">My determination to uncover the truth sometimes leads me to take unnecessary risks.</item>
                <item id="3">I believe that every mystery can be solved with enough time and thought.</item>
                <item id="4">I tend to keep my theories to myself until I have solid evidence.</item>
                <item id="5">I often get lost in my own thoughts and become oblivious to my surroundings.</item>
                <item id="6">I am haunted by a terror afflicting Luyarnha (e.g., Scourge, cults, etc.) and its effects on people, and I won't rest until I've uncovered its origins.</item>
                <item id="7">I often come off as distant or cold, but I'm deeply compassionate towards those affected by the mysteries I investigate.</item>
                <item id="8">I have a cynical sense of humor, often making light of grim situations to keep my spirits up.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
                <item id="1">Truth: I will uncover the truth, no matter how grim or inconvenient it may be. (Neutral)</item>
                <item id="2">Justice: Those responsible for the city's plight must be brought to justice. (Lawful)</item>
                <item id="3">Hope: The truth could lead to salvation. We can't give up hope. (Good)</item>
                <item id="4">Knowledge: Knowledge is power, and I must know it all. (Any)</item>
                <item id="5">Whistleblower: Everyone has the right to know the truth about what's happening in the city. (Chaotic)</item>
                <item id="6">Survival: The mysteries I investigate are a threat to all life. Stopping them is all that matters. (Any)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">I lost someone important to me to the Scourge. I'll do anything to prevent others from experiencing the same pain.</item>
                <item id="2">I was once saved by a hunter, and I owe them a debt I can never repay.</item>
                <item id="3">I have an old friend or mentor who has lost their way. I want to save them.</item>
                <item id="4">I've been bribed to look the other way before, my greed cost many their lives, never again.</item>
                <item id="5">I have a rival investigator who is always one step ahead of me. One day, I will outshine them.</item>
                <item id="6">I believe some people know more about the Scourge than they're letting on. I must uncover their secrets.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">I am so obsessed with my investigations that I often neglect my own well-being.</item>
                <item id="2">I trust my theories more than the testimony of others, which can lead to conflict.</item>
                <item id="3">I have a hard time letting go of unsolved mysteries, even when it's necessary for my safety.</item>
                <item id="4">I enjoy riches, and am not above investigating wealthy individuals to blackmail them later.</item>
                <item id="5">I tend to see mysteries everywhere, even where they don't exist.</item>
                <item id="6">I have a dark secret related to my investigation that I fear others may discover.</item>
            </select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Feature: Scion's Creation" type="Background Feature" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SCION_CREATION">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Your time as a Scion has made you an expert in the creation and maintenance of complex machinery and constructs. You can spend an hour to perform maintenance on a construct, restoring a number of hit points to it equal to your level; a creature can only benefit from this feature once per day. Additionally, you can identify, inspect, and assess the function and value of mechanical or arcane devices or constructs. This does not mean you know how to operate such a device if you have never handled it before. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Scion's Creation" />
	</element>
</elements>