<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Disciple</name>
		<description>Disciple Background</description>
		<author url="">Eldritch Hunt</author>
		<update version="1.0.0">
			<file name="background-disciple.xml" url=""/>
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Disciple" type="Background" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_BACKGROUND_DISCIPLE">
		<description>
			<p>The Radiant Church, a beacon of hope and strength, raised you, training you in the teachings of the Radiant One. As a disciple, you were immersed in the Church's lore, its ideals of benevolence born of resilience and fortitude, and its promise of a prosperous future. You were taught to shine your light into the darkness, to lead the way for others, and to be a pillar of strength in times of adversity. Whether you're an ardent believer, a skeptic questioning your faith, or someone seeking to wield the Church's influence, your time in the Church has undoubtedly shaped your worldview and your identity. </p>
			<ul class="unstyled">
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong>Religion, Persuasion</li>
                <li><strong>Languages:</strong>: One of your choices between Elven and Orcish, representative of the main forces within the Church. </li>
                <li><strong>Tool Proficiencies</strong>Calligrapher's supplies</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong>: A holy symbol of the Radiant One, a prayer book, 5 sticks of incense, vestments, a set of common clothes, and a pouch containing 15 gp</li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DIVINE_GUIDANCE" />
            <div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FORCEFUL_MIRACLE" />
            <div element="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SCRIBE_OF_RADIANCE" />
			<h5>SUGGESTED CHARACTERISTICS</h5>
			<p>You have dedicated your life to the Radiant One, and its teachings have molded you. Your faith may be the source of your strength, or it might be a yoke that weighs you down. Regardless, you are certain of the power of the Church and its role in your life.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">Religion and Persuasion, Choose one between Elven/Orcish, Calligrapher's supplies</set>
        </setters>
		<rules>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_RELIGION"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERSUASION"/>
            <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_TOOL_PROFICIENCY_CALLIGRAPHERS_SUPPLIES"></grant>
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Elven or Orcish)" number="1" supports="Standard||Exotic" />
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DIVINE_GUIDANCE"/>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FORCEFUL_MIRACLE"/>
            <grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SCRIBE_OF_RADIANCE"/>
            <select type="List" name="Personality Trait" number="2">
                <item id="1">I am deeply philosophical and enjoy pondering the mysteries of the universe.</item>
                <item id="2">I'm optimistic and always looking for a silver lining.</item>
                <item id="3">I strive to be a beacon of hope and strength for others.</item>
                <item id="4">I am assertive and never back down from what I believe in.</item>
                <item id="5">I often recount stories and parables from the Radiant Church.</item>
                <item id="6">I always try to offer guidance to those who seem lost.</item>
                <item id="7">I have a peaceful demeanor and a comforting presence.</item>
                <item id="8">I am strict and expect others to abide by the teachings of the Church.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Ideal">
                <item id="1">Strength: I must be strong so that I can guide others through adversity. (Lawful)</item>
                <item id="2">Hope: I am a beacon of light in the darkness, showing the way to a brighter future. (Good)</item>
                <item id="3">Faith: My faith in the Radiant One gives me strength and purpose. (Any)</item>
                <item id="4">Knowledge: The true path to enlightenment is the pursuit of knowledge. (Neutral)</item>
                <item id="5">Charity: It's my duty to help those in need, and to provide for the less fortunate. (Good)</item>
                <item id="6">Independence: I must question and challenge my faith to truly understand it. (Chaotic)</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Bond">
                <item id="1">I owe my life to the Church, and I will serve it until my last breath.</item>
                <item id="2">I believe that the Radiant One has a grand destiny in store for me.</item>
                <item id="3">I will bring the teachings of the Radiant Church to those who live in darkness.</item>
                <item id="4">I aim to preserve the unity of the Church amidst its division into factions.</item>
                <item id="5">I feel responsible for those who stray from the path of the Radiant One.</item>
                <item id="6">I will redeem the Church from its insidious corruption and restore its noble ideals.</item>
            </select>
            <select type="List" name="Flaw">
                <item id="1">I am dogmatic and find it hard to accept beliefs that contradict the teachings of the Church.</item>
                <item id="2">I am naive and often overoptimistic, which sometimes leads me to underestimate dangers.</item>
                <item id="3">I am plagued by an overwhelming fear of divine judgment, constantly doubting whether my actions are in accordance with the teachings of my faith.</item>
                <item id="4">I struggle with doubt and question my faith, particularly when facing the unfairness of life.</item>
                <item id="5">I have high expectations for myself and others, which often leads to disappointment.</item>
                <item id="6">I find it hard to forgive myself for past mistakes and often dwell on them.</item>
            </select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	
	<element name="Feature: Divine Guidance" type="Background Feature" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_DIVINE_GUIDANCE">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You have spent countless hours praying, studying scriptures, and performing rituals. Your devotion is so great that it draws the attention of the Radiant One, or so you believe. You can call upon this divine favor to guide your path. Once per day, you may ask your deity for guidance. How this guidance manifests can vary—a sudden insight, a prophetic dream, or perhaps a subtlesign in the environment around you.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Divine Guidance" />
	</element>
    
    <element name="Feature: Forceful Miracle" type="Background Feature" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_FORCEFUL_MIRACLE">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Through your dedicated service, you have harnessed the powers of the Radiant One. In the most dire of situations, you may extract this power for a miracle. However, these miracles are not to be taken lightly and should not be used frivolously. The miracle cannot be stronger in power than a spell of level equal to half your character level (rounded down, minimum 1st level). After a miracle has been granted, your hit points maximum are lowered by an amount equal to your character level for 1d12 days, and you must perform a significant service for the Radiant One to regain this miracle. </p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Forceful Miracle" />
	</element>
    
    <element name="Feature: Scribe of Radiance" type="Background Feature" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_SCRIBE_OF_RADIANCE">
		<supports>Background Feature</supports>
		<description>
			<p>You've spent years studying the ancient scripts and texts of the Radiant Church, and with time, you've become a skilled scribe. Not only can you flawlessly replicate any scripture, but you can also identify and understand most religious texts related to your faith. This ability can prove invaluable when deciphering forgotten scriptures or understanding cryptic prophecies.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Scribe of Radiancet" />
	</element>
</elements>