<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Demidritch</name>
		<update version="1.0.0">
			<file name="race-demidritch.xml" url="" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Demidritch" type="Race" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_RACE_DEMIDRITCH">
		<description>
			<p class="flavor">irises that swirl like galaxies in a jet-black sclera—demidritch occupy a precarious precipice in the minds of Luyarnhians, equal parts revered and abhorred. Born of a union between humanoids and eldritch beings, demidritch are often referred to as ‘half-angels’, a misnomer arising from Luyarnhians’ mistaken belief that these creatures are descended from celestials. Stories abound of radiant silhouettes—eldritch creatures wreathed in powerful illusions—appearing unto pregnant Luyarnhians and blessing their progeny with otherworldly powers. While the Radiant Church espouses no stance on the morality of such beings, elements amongst their ranks, most notably the bookish Obitus Scholare, prize the demidritch as precious specimens that may provide the key to humanity's survival. The deeds of the righteous demidritch Aitzaz, a first hunter and close friend of Steinhardt, are widely recounted by bards and minstrels across the city. His death at the hands of the ravenous scourge while evacuating schoolchildren precipitated a shift in the treatment of demidritch by Luyarnhians. Though they may have otherworldly origins, the alignment of demidritch, like most humanoids, is a product of their environment and upbringing.</p>
            <p class="origin">The act of childbearing is, in itself, a heroic endeavor that women courageously undertake, placing their bodies at risk to ensure the perpetuation of their lineage into the distant future. In most societies, this sacred act has been revered; yet, within the confines of Luyarnha, it can assume an unsettling guise. In this city, certain women find themselves beset by nightmares, only to awaken and, within mere days, experience the telltale nausea of pregnancy, despite their unblemished chastity: blessed by the offspring of a Higher Power—or so it is believed. While some regard this union as a divine blessing, it cruelly prevents the expecting mother from ever establishing a family, for the demidritch offspring rends the womb asunder with their foreign constitution during birth. Should the trauma not be swiftly attended to, the mother's life can meet an abrupt end. In response, the church has taken to gathering those who exhibit this miraculous conception to ensure their safety during labor and to exert a modicum of control over the potent half-divine progeny. For some women, particularly those of faith or those deemed unworthy of love, the prospect of receiving this so-called blessing is welcomed. Such a union would grant them sanctuary within the church's protective walls for the remainder of their lives, offering them the semblance of a family they might not have otherwise known, however fractured it may be. Yet, others are repulsed by this fate and seek to defy it, often with tragic results. Those who reject the church's embrace might give birth in forsaken alleyways, casting their children away or consigning them to orphanages. A fortunate few, perhaps bolstered by exceptional financial fortitude or familial support, succeed in bearing their offspring and providing them with as normal a childhood as Luyarnha's grim circumstances allow. This enigmatic phenomenon has left even the most erudite scholars utterly perplexed. It is widely accepted that the Great Ones are incapable of procreation, and yet. Various theories have been postulated in an attempt to fathom the origins of these peculiar offspring—some conjecture that they serve as beacons, as the Great Ones disseminate their consciousness across the vast reaches of the cosmos, with fragments ultimately embedding themselves within the bodies of these unsuspecting mothers; consequently, the resulting progeny would function as a beacon to draw the Great Ones nearer to the world—others suggest that, due to their intrinsic sterility, the Great Ones crave a surrogate through which to vicariously experience creation. However, the motives of these enigmatic entities are, by their very nature, inscrutable to the mortal mind, and any attempt to decipher their intentions is inherently constrained and flawed.</p>
            <h4>CURSED-BLOOD TRAITS</h4>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Charisma score increases by 2</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Age.</em></strong> Demidritchs mature faster than humans, reaching adulthood after 10 years. Their eldritch powers cause their body to decay much faster, they can live up to 60 years old.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Darkvision</em></strong> Your many eyes were made to see through the darkness of space. You can see in dim light within 120 feet of you as if it were bright light, and in darkness as if it were dim light. You can't discern color in darkness, only shades of gray.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Size.</em></strong>  Demidritchs have the same range of height and weight as humans. Your size is Medium. </p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Speed.</em></strong> Your base walking speed is 30 feet</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Languages.</em></strong> You can speak, read, and write Common and Deep Speech.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Shard of Infinity</em></strong> You are born of the galaxies and their endless void. You have resistance to cold damage.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Astral Being</em></strong>  Your many eyes grant you sight. You have advantage on saving throws against being blinded</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Subrace.</em></strong> Depending on their lineage, demidritchs have different subraces, which represent their variation. The DC for abilities given by the subraces is equal to 8 + twice your proficiency bonus.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<setters>
			<set name="height" modifier="2d10">4'0"</set>
			<set name="weight" modifier="1d4">100 lb.</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<stat name="charisma" value="2" />
			<stat name="innate speed" value="30" bonus="base" />
			<grant type="Size" id="ID_SIZE_MEDIUM" />
			<grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_COMMON"/>
            <grant type="Language" id="ID_LANGUAGE_DEEP_SPEECH"/>
            <grant type="Vision" id="ID_VISION_SUPERIORDARKVISION"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SHARD_OF_INFINITY" />
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_ASTRAL_BEING"/>
			<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_DEMIDRITCH_SUBRACE" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Shard of Infinity" type="Racial Trait" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_SHARD_OF_INFINITY">
		<description>
			<p>You are born of the galaxies and their endless void. You have resistance to cold damage.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You are born of the galaxies and their endless void. You have resistance to cold damage.</description>
		</sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_COLD"/>
        </rules>
	</element>
    
    <element name="Astral Being" type="Racial Trait" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_ASTRAL_BEING">
		<description>
			<p>Your many eyes grant you sight. You have advantage on saving throws against being blinded</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your many eyes grant you sight. You have advantage on saving throws against being blinded</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
    
	<element name="Demidritch Subrace" type="Racial Trait" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_DEMIDRITCH_SUBRACE">
		<description>
			<p>Depending on their lineage, demidritchs have different subraces, which represent their variation. The DC for abilities given by the subraces is equal to 8 + twice your proficiency bonus.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<select type="Sub Race" name="Demidritch Subrace" supports="Demidritch"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
    
    <element name="Oculare" type="Sub Race" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_SUB_RACE_OCULARE">
	<supports>Demidritch</supports>
	<description>
		<p>Also called observers, the many-eyed, and watchers, oculare always possess a greater allocation of eyes than one might expect. Commoners often describe the feeling of being watched when in the presence of oculare; in fact, such individuals commonly find themselves in the employ of the militia or church as investigators, their natural perceptiveness giving them a keen advantage.</p>
		<p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Consititution score increases by 1.</p>
		<p class="indent"><strong><em>All Seeing Eyes</em></strong>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your action to unleash your progenitor’s eldritch energy, causing eyes that glow with an ethereal quality to open along your body and clothing for 1 minute. For the duration, creatures within 60 feet of you can’t gain advantage on attack rolls against you as a result of being invisible or unseen.
        Starting at level 12 you also grow eye-covered eldritch wings which grant you a flying speed of 30 feet and the ability to see invisibility out to a range of 60 feet. Once you use this traiy, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest</p>
        <p class="indent"><strong><em>Watcher</em></strong>You are proficient in the Perception skill.</p>
	</description>
	<sheet display="false" />
	<rules>
		<stat name="constitution" value="1"/>
        <grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SKILL_PERCEPTION"/>
		<grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_ALL_SEEING_EYES" />
	</rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Nebulare" type="Sub Race" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_SUB_RACE_NEBULARE">
        <supports>Demidritch</supports>
        <description>
            <p>Beneath the translucent skin of the nebulare flit constellations of multihued lights: galaxy-like swirls and nebulous clouds. In times of great peril, these colourful displays can erupt in a supernova-like display of radiant brilliance, creating localised gravitational fields that help ensure the escape, and continued proliferation, of the nebular demidritch. 
            Though the progenitor of the nebulare, an Outer God, has created no new nabulare for some time, the bloodline can go dormant for several generations, manifesting seemingly at random among newborns. Of course, with the Radiant Church experimentation in full swing, whether or not the recurrence of nebulare is really at random is an unanswered question. </p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Ability Score Increase.</em></strong> Your Strength score increases by 1.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Astral Attraction</em></strong>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your action to unleash the potential energy within yourself, causing your body to erupt with power and transforming it for 1 minute. When you first transform, each creature other than you in a 10-foot radius centered on you must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take a number of d6s of radiant damage from the explosion equal to your proficiency bonus. 
            While transformed in this way, you shed bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. You generate a powerful gravitational field. The area within a 20-foot radius centered on you is considered difficult terrain for creatures of your choice that you can see. Starting at level 12, this radius increases to 60 feet and you can ignore gravity, granting a flying speed of 30 feet during which you can hover. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
            <p class="indent"><strong><em>Glow</em></strong> You can cast the light cantrip on your own body at will.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet>
            <description>You know the light cantrip. Which you can cast on your body at will</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <stat name="strength" value="1"/>
            <grant type="Racial Trait" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_ASTRAL_ATTRACTION" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHT"/>
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="All Seeing Eyes" type="Racial Trait" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_ALL_SEEING_EYES">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your action to unleash your progenitor’s eldritch energy, causing eyes that glow with an ethereal quality to open along your body and clothing for 1 minute. For the duration, creatures within 60 feet of you can’t gain advantage on attack rolls against you as a result of being invisible or unseen. Starting at level 12 you also grow eye-covered eldritch wings which grant you a flying speed of 30 feet and the ability to see invisibility out to a range of 60 feet. Once you use this traiy, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="Long Rest">
            <description level="1"></description>
            <description level="3">You can use your action to unleash your progenitor’s eldritch energy, causing eyes that glow with an ethereal quality to open along your body and clothing for 1 minute. For the duration, creatures within 60 feet of you can’t gain advantage on attack rolls against you as a result of being invisible or unseen.</description>
            <description level="12">You can use your action to unleash your progenitor’s eldritch energy, causing eyes that glow with an ethereal quality to open along your body and clothing for 1 minute. For the duration, creatures within 60 feet of you can’t gain advantage on attack rolls against you as a result of being invisible or unseen.You also grow eye-covered eldritch wings which grant you a flying speed of 30 feet and the ability to see invisibility out to a range of 60 feet.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Astral Attraction" type="Racial Trait" source="Eldritch Hunt" id="ID_RACIAL_TRAIT_ASTRAL_ATTRACTION">
        <description>
            <p>Starting at 3rd level, you can use your action to unleash the potential energy within yourself, causing your body to erupt with power and transforming it for 1 minute. When you first transform, each creature other than you in a 10-foot radius centered on you must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take a number of d6s of radiant damage from the explosion equal to your proficiency bonus. 
            While transformed in this way, you shed bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. You generate a powerful gravitational field. The area within a 20-foot radius centered on you is considered difficult terrain for creatures of your choice that you can see. Starting at level 12, this radius increases to 60 feet and you can ignore gravity, granting a flying speed of 30 feet during which you can hover. Once you use this trait, you can't use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
        </description>
        <sheet action="Action" usage="Long Rest">
            <description level="1"></description>
            <description level="3">You can use your action to unleash the potential energy within yourself, causing your body to erupt with power and transforming it for 1 minute. When you first transform, each creature other than you in a 10-foot radius centered on you must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take a number of d6s of radiant damage from the explosion equal to your proficiency bonus. While transformed in this way, you shed bright light in a 10-foot radius and dim light for an additional 10 feet. You generate a powerful gravitational field. The area within a 20-foot radius centered on you is considered difficult terrain for creatures of your choice that you can see.</description>
            <description level="12">You can use your action to unleash the potential energy within yourself, causing your body to erupt with power and transforming it for 1 minute. When you first transform, each creature other than you in a 60-foot radius centered on you must succeed on a Dexterity saving throw or take a number of d6s of radiant damage from the explosion equal to your proficiency bonus. While transformed in this way, you shed bright light in a 60-foot radius and dim light for an additional 60 feet. You generate a powerful gravitational field. The area within a 20-foot radius centered on you is considered difficult terrain for creatures of your choice that you can see.You can ignore gravity, granting a flying speed of 30 feet during which you can hover.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>
    </elements>
