<elements>
<info>
    <name>Feats</name>
    <description>Feats from Dragon Age</description>
    <update version="7.0.0">
        <file name="feats.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/MonallCone/Aurora_Custom_Files/refs/heads/main/Dragon%20Age/feats.xml"/>
</update>
</info>
    <element name="Blood Magic" type="Feat" source="Dragon Age" id="ID_DA_FEAT_BLOOD_MAGIC">
        <prerequisites>Wizard, Sorceror, Warlock, Bard or Druid</prerequisites>
        <requirements>[wizard:1]||[warlock:1]||[sorcerer:1]||[bard:1]||[druid:1]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Through forbidden rituals or a cursed lineage, you have delved into the sinister art of blood magic. This dark and taboo practice draws upon the life essence of the caster or others, turning vitality into raw power. The corrupting influence of blood magic has left its mark on you, granting you abilities feared and reviled by many.</p>
            <ul>
                <li>Increase your Intelligence, Wisdom, or Charisma score by 1, to a maximum of 20.</li>
                <li>You learn three Blood Magic cantrips of your choice from the Blood Magic spell list.</li>
                <li>For each spell level available to you, you gain access to one Blood Magic spell of your choice from the Blood Magic spell list. These spells are in addition to your known spells and can be cast as detailed below:
                    <ul>
                        <li>You must activate Blood Magic Mode as an action to cast Blood Magic spells.</li>
                        <li>While in Blood Magic Mode, you may cast Blood Magic spells by either expending spell slots or substituting hit points.</li>
                        <li>Casting Blood Magic spells costs:
                            <ul>
                                <li>Cantrip: 1 hit point.</li>
                                <li>Levelled spells: 4 × the spell’s level in hit points.</li>
                            </ul>
                        </li>
                        <li>You may use your own hit points, a willing ally’s, or pool hit points from multiple willing creatures within 30 feet to pay the cost.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>When a magical mishap occurs due to a Blood Magic spell:
                    <ul>
                        <li>If hit points were used to cast the spell, you immediately gain 2 Corruption Points and must roll on the Magical Mishap table.</li>
                        <li>If a spell slot was used, proceed with the mishap saving throw as normal.</li>
                    </ul>
                </li>
                <li>Upon gaining this feat, you immediately accrue 3 Corruption Points as the price for treading this dark and dangerous path.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="Action">
            <description>Activate Blood Magic Mode as an action to cast Blood Magic spells. Pay the cost in hit points or spell slots as described in the feat.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase, Blood Magic" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Blood Magic (Cantrip)" supports="0,Blood Magic" level="1" number="3"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Blood Magic Spell (1st Level)" supports="1,Blood Magic" level="1" number="1"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Blood Magic Spell (2nd Level)" supports="2,Blood Magic" level="3" number="1"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Blood Magic Spell (3rd Level)" supports="3,Blood Magic" level="5" number="1"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Blood Magic Spell (4th Level)" supports="4,Blood Magic" level="7" number="1"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Blood Magic Spell (5th Level)" supports="5,Blood Magic" level="9" number="1"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="Blood Magic Spell (6th Level)" supports="6,Blood Magic" level="11" number="1"/>
        </rules>
    </element>
    
    <element name="Dreamer" type="Feat" source="Dragon Age" id="ID_DA_FEAT_DREAMER">
        <prerequisites>Mage Classes</prerequisites>
        <requirements>[wizard:1]||[warlock:1]||[sorcerer:1]||[bard:1]||[druid:1]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>Your connection to the Fade allows you to tap into dreamlike energies and ethereal knowledge. Whether through training or a deep mystical bond, you have learned to draw on the Fade’s power to bend reality in subtle and unique ways.
            
            As a Dreamer, you possess the ability to slip in and out of the Fade, a mystical realm of dreams and spirits, much like those who undergo a Harrowing However, unlike the Harrowing, you do not require lyrium to enter this realm. Be warned: the Fade is a realm fraught with danger. The longer you remain there, the more likely you are to attract the attention of spirits or demons, who may seek to possess you or manipulate your mind. You may occasionally be tempted or coerced into staying within the Fade longer than you intend</p>
            <ul>
                <li>You gain 1 corruption point when taking this feat expressing the danger found in the fade and how your unique presense when there attracts various demons and spirits</li>
                <li>Ritual Casting: You learn one ritual spell of your choice from the Divination, Illusion, or Necromancy schools of magic. This spell can be of a level you can cast, and it does not count against your number of spells known. You can cast this spell as a ritual without expending a spell slot, following the normal rules for ritual casting.</li>
                <li>Dreamstrider: Increase 1 ability score of your choice, Charisma, Intelligence or Wisdom</li>
                <li>Fade’s Embrace: You can cast Fade Step once per long rest without expending a spell slot. When you do, you momentarily phase into the Fade and reappear in the physical world, leaving behind an ethereal afterimage for a brief moment. </li>
                <li>Unearthly Knowledge: You can speak, read, and understand one language of your choice from creatures that dwell within the Fade, such as spirits, demons, or ancient beings. This language may also be one tied to dreams or long-lost knowledge.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
            <description>You can cast Fade Step as a 1st Level Spell once per long rest without expending a spell slot.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <select type="Ability Score Improvement" name="Ability Score Increase, Dreamer" supports="ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_INTELLIGENCE|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_WISDOM|ID_PHB_FEAT_ASI_CHARISMA"/>
            <select type="Spell" name="1st Level Spell (Dreamer)" supports="Ritual,1" number="1" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_DA_SPELL_FADE_STEP" />
            <select type="Language" name="Language (Dreamer)" number="1"/>   
        </rules>
    </element>

    <element name="Tempest" type="Feat" source="Dragon Age" id="ID_DA_FEAT_TEMPEST">
        <prerequisites>Non Mage Classes</prerequisites>
        <requirements>[fighter:1]||[barbarian:1]||[rogue:1]||[monk:1]||[ranger:1]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>You have learned to harness the power of elemental salves, coating yourself and your weapons in raw elemental energy to enhance your combat prowess. Upon taking this feat, you gain the following benefits:</p>
        <ul>
            <li><strong>Elemental Coating:</strong> As a bonus action, you can use one of your salves to coat yourself in an elemental essence. Choose one of the following damage types: <em>fire, cold, or lightning</em>. For 1 minute:
                <ul>
                    <li>You gain resistance to the chosen damage type.</li>
                    <li>All weapon and spell damage you deal is converted into the chosen damage type.</li>
                    <li>Damage of the chosen type ignores resistance <em>only if the damage would normally already be of that type (e.g., a spell or weapon attack inherently dealing the chosen damage).</em></li>
                </ul>
            </li>
            <li>You can use each salve (<em>fire, cold, lightning</em>) only once per long rest.</li>
        </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="3/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
            <description>Coat yourself in an elemental salve, granting resistance and converting your damage to the chosen element (<em>fire, cold, lightning</em>), If the damage would normally already be of that type it ignores resistance. Each element can only be used once per long rest.</description>
        </sheet>
    </element>

    <element name="Mortalitasi" type="Feat" source="Dragon Age" id="ID_DA_FEAT_MORTALITASI">
        <prerequisites>Mage Classes</prerequisites>
        <requirements>[wizard:1]||[warlock:1]||[sorcerer:1]||[bard:1]||[druid:1]</requirements>
        <description>
            <p>The Mortalitasi are a specialized order of necromancers from Nevarra, known as "Death Mages." These mages believe that when a soul crosses the Fade, it displaces a spirit. They invite these displaced spirits to house themselves in the bodies left behind, particularly mummified corpses. Through their practice, Mortalitasi mages commune with the dead, channel the power of spirits, and raise the deceased as servants to fulfill their unfinished business.</p>
            <ul>
                <li><b>Speak with the Dead:</b> You learn the Speak with Dead ritual, which you can cast once per long rest without expending a spell slot. Through this ritual, you can speak with the souls of the dead, asking them questions to learn of their pasts and gain insight into the world beyond the Veil.</li>
                <li><b>Spirit Summoning:</b>You gain the Will O Wisp spell and As a bonus action, you can summon a wisp spirit from the Fade. You can cast this spell once as a first level spell without expdending a spell slot </li>
                <li><b>Animate Undead:</b> Once per long rest, you can raise one undead creature without expending a spell slot. The undead creature must be a humanoid or beast that has died within the last 24 hours, and it remains under your control for 1 hour. When the undead is summoned, the wisp spirit will possess the body, granting an aura to the undead and allies within 10 feet of it. The aura provides a 1d6 bonus to saving throws based on the spirit’s nature.</li>
            </ul>
        </description>
        <sheet usage="1/Long Rest" action="Bonus Action">
            <description>You can Cast a level 1 Will O Wisp spell without expending a spell slot. you can raise one undead creature without expending a spell slot in which the wisp will possess granting it a 10ft aura of 1d6 bonus to saving throws based on the spirit’s nature to friendly creatures.</description>
        </sheet>
        <rules>
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_DA_SPELL_WILL_O_WISP" />
            <grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD" /> 
        </rules>
    </element>
</elements>